in this exercise
we want to validate not only a password
but a username as well so we're going to
be working with two pieces of
information
the first step is just to determine a
username
and we will define that with a constant
as well
[Music]
let's call it admin
so we're going to prompt the user two
separate times
we'll leave our prompt for the user's
password as
is but now we also want to prompt them
for their username
so we'll have a similar prompt here
please enter your username
and we'll hold the user input in
a local variable called username
[Music]
we want our username to be case
sensitive just like our password
so we won't down case this user input as
it comes in
now let's see what happens if we run the
program as is
[Music]
let me put in an incorrect username
and now i'll input the correct password
[Music]
the program welcomes us you can see that
right now
our input validation is only checking
for a correct password
so we need to alter that so that we're
verifying that the correct password has
been input
as well as the correct username let's
look at our break condition
on line 11. we're already comparing the
user input for
the password to our password constant
and now we need to validate the username
input as well
and we can do that using the same syntax
however we need to use the and operator
now the conditional we've provided our
if statement
will only evaluate to true if the
expressions on both the left
and right side of the and operator
evaluate to true
so if either one of these is false then
our loop will continue
let's test this out
this time i'll enter the correct
username
and an incorrect password
the error message issued is invalid
password
but the prompt begins again at please
enter your username
this time let's enter an incorrect
username
and the correct password
so our loop is behaving as we intend
it's not breaking if either one of these
is incorrect
however the error message being issued
right now needs to change because
currently
it tells us that we have an invalid
password under
any condition
let's enter the correct input for both
options
and we've broken out of the loop and the
program welcomes us
[Music]
so let's go back and change this error
message
now you'll notice that if the user input
is incorrect for either the username
or the password we start at the top of
the loop again
and prompt for both the username and
password again
we're going to expect that the user
input both the correct username and
password
without us telling them which one was
wrong
so rather than issue an error message
telling them
whether the username or password or both
were wrong
we're simply going to tell them
authorization failed
this time i'll enter an incorrect
username
and an incorrect password
the program tells us that authorization
failed
let's enter the correct username this
time
and an incorrect password
you can see that the error message is
the same
we'll run the code one more time with an
incorrect username
and the correct password
and again see that the error message is
the same anytime
our input is incorrect
finally i'll enter the correct username
and the correct password and our code is
working just as we expect